Guide to the Southeastern Women's Studies Association Records, 1977-2006 RL.01169
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southeastern Women's Studies Association records
1977-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Southeastern Women's Studies Association
RL.01169
2.0 Linear Feet
Group based in Southeastern United States, founded in 1977 at the first National Women's Studies Association Convention. SEWSA is committed to the promotion and support of women's studies and women's advocacy in schools, universities, and communities. Includes correspondence, minutes, newsletters, membership lists, papers presented at conferences, 12 photographs, SEWSA conference materials, and travel grant files. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
1350 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Southeastern Women's Studies Association Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Historical Note
The Southeastern Women's Studies Association, founded in Atlanta in 1977, is a regional organization under the National Women's Studies Association. SEWSA members includes individuals, institutions, students, and faculty, and the organization serves Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and Virginia. According to its website, SEWSA is a feminist organization committed to scholarship, activism against oppression and discrimination, and the promotion of women's studies. It does this through a newsletter, annual conferences and workshops, travel grants for students, and networking within various women's studies departments. For more information on SEWSA, refer to their website: http://sewsa.nwsa.org/index.html
Collection Overview
Accession (2006-0065) contains a variety of administrative, business, financial, and other materials relating to the operation of the Southeastern Women's Studies Association. The majority of the materials date from 1985 through the mid-1990s, with additional items from both before and after that period.
Files have been loosely arranged into series. The Administrative and Business Records series includes the organization's bylaws and its subsequent updates; correspondence; agendas and meeting minutes from committees and business meetings; financial statements and accounts; conference proposals and some conference papers; travel grant materials; membership lists and addresses; stationary and other templates; and lists of officers and committee members from various points throughout the organization's history. Conference planning is a large component of this series, resulting in some overlap with the Conferences series. Another notable portion is the files relating to SEWSA's travel grants, which include both applications, acceptances, and information about the grant program. This series has been largely sorted by date, with occassional subjects filed separately.
The Conferences series include conference planning materials, as mentioned above, as well as conference programs and calls for papers announcements. The Newsletters series includes a run of the newsletters as well as newsletter preparation files from the 1980s. Finally, there are also some conference and SEWSA buttons as well as a SEWSA 1985 t-shirt present in the Ephemera series.
Women's studies -- Conferences; Feminism -- United States -- History; Women's studies -- Research; Women -- United States -- History; Southeastern Women's Studies Association
- Administrative and Business Materials, 2 boxes
  - By-laws, circa 1979-2003 (Box 1)
  - Chronological files, 1981-1996 (11 folders) (Box 1)
  - Travel grant information, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
  - Travel grants, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chronological files, 1997-1999 (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - NWSA and SEWSA membership project, 1977 and no date (Box 2)
  - Membership and mailing lists, 1990-2003 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Gay and Lesbian literature, 2002-2003 and no date (Box 2)
  - Membership forms, no date (Box 2)
  - Stationary, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Graphics, no date (Box 2)
  - Letterhead, no date (Box 2)
  - Founding Mothers panel, 1997
- Conferences, 3 boxes
  - University of Alabama, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Appalachian State, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt, 1987 (Box 2)
  - UNC-Chapel Hill, 1988 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Emory University, 1989 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Eastern Carolina University, 1994 (Box 2)
  - University of Florida, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Florida Atlantic University, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Calls for papers, 1984-2000 (Box 3)
  - Conference programs, 1984-2006 (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Charlotte, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Johnson City, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Richmond, 1996 (Box 4)
  - University of Georgia, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Georgia State University, 2010 (Box 4)
  - Atlanta, 2011 (Box 4)
- Newsletters, 1 box
  - Materials, 1982-1986 (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Newsletters, 1983-2003 (2 folders) (Box 3)
- Ephemera, 1 box
  - Buttons (Box 3)
  - 1985 SEWSA t-shirt (Box 3)